

377 R. O'Connor St, Ottawa, ON K2P 2M2, Canada

Summary

Results-driven Software Engineer with almost 2 years of experience, specializing in backend development (java). Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools. Looking for a team with an open mind and positive thinking. Have more than 7 years of experience as a telecom engineer.

Work Experience

Skai Kyiv, Ukraine - Tel Aviv, Israel

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mar. 2022 - Present

- Finished big project (9 months) with team. Added new channel and new features to our omnichannel. This brought new customers and large contracts
- Reworked synchronization between two big services of our system by moving from Hibernate to PL (jOOQ) which led to fail safe and 99% more stable synchronization
- Enhanced one of the microservices, this included extending the structure of objects, improving validation on both back and front ends, increasing test coverage. These changes allowed us to add a new complex feature

Realpad Praque, Czechia

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mar. 2021 - Mar. 2022

- · Migrated old pages from JSP to Spring Boot for faster download speed, more security and robust code
- Participated in site renewing by migrating it from JSP and plain HTML to Spring Boot and jQuery, this brought more security, stability, faster loading speed, etc
- Was in a team responsible for quick adding small fixes and improvements or additional features which impacted keeping client retention rate 94% and above
- Made settings page more client friendly by adding dynamic descriptions which led to less clients asking about it in CS team by around 15%

Skills_

Java, Spring, Spring Boot, MySQL, JDBC, Hibernate, jOOQ, Liquibase, Redis, Docker, Maven, Gradle, Microservices, Jenkins, Git, Kafka, DataDog, Guice, ProtoBuf, CI/CD, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JUnit, Mockito, Cucumber, Karate

Education

Kamianets-Podilskyi Ivan Ohiienko National University

Ukraine

MASTER'S DEGREE IN MANAGEMENT OF ORGANIZATIONS

Mar. 2019 - Dec. 2020

State Agrarian And Engineering University In Podilia

MASTER'S DEGREE IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Ukraine Sep. 2007 - May. 2012

DECEMBER 8, 2022 MYKHAILO RYZAK · RÉSUMÉ